Connecticut League for Nursing Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut League for Nursing Records.
undated, 1952-2003.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center
Connecticut League for Nursing.
4.25 cubic feet.
MSS20030083
Administrative records of the Connecticut League for Nursing whose mission is to: foster partnerships between academic and clinical nursing leaders; facilitate access to formal nursing education programs in the State of Connecticut; provide affordable, accessible, and contemporary continuing education programs and forums; and support the National League for Nursing's initiatives related to Nurse Faculty Development, Nursing Research and Nursing Workforce Demographics (from CLN mission statement).
History
On 10 December 1952, the first formal organizational meeting of the Connecticut League for Nursing was held at Heublein Hall in Hartford Hospital. Ruth M. Olson, Director of Nursing at New Britain Memorial Hospital, was elected the first President. Dues were $5 and there were 338 charter members and 37 friends of nursing.
The vision of CLN's original founders continues today through the League's current programs and activities as guided by the current Mission Statement:
"The Connecticut League for Nursing advances and strengthens the nursing profession by providing education for and facilitating collaboration among educators, practitioners, administrators, consumers and other stakeholders to meet the needs of diverse populations in an ever-changing healthcare environment."
Additional information can be found on the Connecticut League for Nursing website.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, reports, publications, administrative and financial records documenting the activities and interests of the organization.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged into one alphabetical series.
Series I: Records, ( undated, 1952-2003 ) includes administrative and financial records of the organization as well as publications, photographs and ephemera.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to nursing education and leadership. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Diploma School of Nursing in the 1908s. Dodd C7149
Guide to Nursing Education in Connecticut. Dodd Periodicals
Health Resources News. Dodd Periodicals
Nursing needs and Resources in Connecticut. A Report of the Connecticut Commission on Nursing. Dodd C7140
Roots of Interpersonal Nursing. Dodd A5573
Story of the National League of Nursing Education. Dodd A5572
"Virginia Henderson at the Connecticut League for Nursing" 2003-0083.vr1
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Connecticut League for Nursing.
Subjects:
Nursing administrators--Education.; Professional associations--Connecticut.; Nursing--Study and teaching.; Nursing--Connecticut History.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Press releases.; Videocassettes.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Bylaws.; Newsletters.
Occupations:
Nursing.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated by the Connecticut League for Nursing in 2003.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Records, undated, 1952-2003
  - Advanced Placement Information, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - All State Scholarships, undated, 1962-1968 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1979 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Board of Nursing Examiners, 1977-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Brochures--Membership, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Brochures and pamphlets, undated, 1985-2001 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Bylaws, 1969-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Bylaws and amendments, 1952-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Calendar, 1986-1987 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Clock, undated (Box 7)
  - Continuing Education, 1975-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Continuing Education for Nurses, 1975-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Council--CNA-CLN, 1960, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence--program Coordinator, 1978-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Council of Nurse Managers, 1979 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Educational Grants to CLN, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Effie J. Taylor Award, 1968-1970 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Executive Director, undated, 1986 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Finance Committee, 1974-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Financial Statements, 1957-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Financial Statements, 1979-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Friends of Nursing Campaign, 1972-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Guide to Nursing Education, undated, 1975-1994 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Historian, 1953-1954 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Historical Information, Charter Members, undated,1962-1970 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Historical materials, 1967-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Historical Source Materials, 1967-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - History, undated, 1952-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - History of the Connecticut League for Nursing compiled by Eleanor Lundblad, undated (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Honorary membership, 1969-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Ledger, 1953-1954 (Box 6:, Folder 81)
  - Legislative issues, 1983-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - Maternal and Child Health Council, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Membership materials, 1972-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Minutes--Board, 1970-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - Minutes--Board, 1978-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Minutes--Board, 1992-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 38-39)
  - Minutes--Board, 1992-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 40-41)
  - Minutes--Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1985-1986 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1987-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1989-1990 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1990-1991 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1992-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - Minutes--Council of Deans/Directors, 1993-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - National league for Nursing, 1974-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
  - National league for Nursing Awards, undated, 1976-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Newsletters, 1977-2003 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - Newsletters/Program Brochures, 1976-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - Nurse of the Year Pageant, 1983 (Box 6:, Folder 82)
  - Nurses Education Foundation, undated (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - Past President--Bauiley, Allison M., 1973-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
  - Past President--Health, Mary B., 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 55)
  - Past President--Scales, Carol J., 1975-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 5)
  - Press Releases, 1977-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Program Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
  - Psychiatric/Mental Health Nursing, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
  - Quality of Life for Connecticut children, 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
  - Reports--Annual, 1959-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - Reports--Annual, 1960-1969 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - Reports--Annual, 1962-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - Reports--State Board Exam, ca. 1957 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - Reports--Treasurer, 1953-1967 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
  - Reports--Treasurer, 1971-1973 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
  - Recruitment, 1976-2003 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
  - Retirement Plan, 1965-1973 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
  - Steering Committee--Division of Nursing Services Bylaws, 1953, 1961 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
  - Yearbook
    - 1982-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 3:, Folder 71-72)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 3:, Folder 73)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 3:, Folder 74)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 3:, Folder 75)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 4:, Folder 76)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 4:, Folder 77-78)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 4:, Folder 79-80)